<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>HyperText Thrones</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-12-31T22:35:30+07:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Deden Fathurahman</name>
   <email>dedenf@gmail.com</email>
   <twitter>dedenf</twitter>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>720p vs 1080p vs 1080i vs 4K</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/different-pixel"/>
   <updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/different-pixel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/pixel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;versus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/unixstickers/status/947110842218278912&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #25</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-25"/>
   <updated>2017-12-28T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-25</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/iphone-battery-and-performance/&quot;&gt;Apple letter about the iPhone battery&lt;/a&gt; – it’s not that i hate Apple, none of my opinion matters anyway, but i feel like Apple is downgrading itself in terms of vision, quality, security, smartness. i even &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.dedenf.com/2017/12/worst-macbookpro&quot;&gt;ranting about my Macbook Pro&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed style title&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newstatesman.com/culture/books/2017/12/beneath-another-sky-historian-s-revisionist-global-take-migration-and-identity&quot;&gt;Beneath Another Sky: a historian’s revisionist, global take on migration and identity&lt;/a&gt; – As an individu, we probably think that we are much better than anyone else, combine that with the same culture, background, religion, etc and you became a group of people, and will likely hate other group that have different background, culture, skin color, religion. and mob mentality came in. it’s easy to spot on indonesian society, different opinion and you will have a judgement or worst case, killed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/12/28/16747680/2017-verge-illustrations&quot;&gt;The Verge illustration through the year&lt;/a&gt; – Awesome illustration from the verge illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/rondy/af1dee1d28c02e9a225ae55da2674a6f&quot;&gt;Effective Engineer&lt;/a&gt; – an opinion how to be an effective engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #24</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-24"/>
   <updated>2017-12-27T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-24</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.justinobeirne.com/google-maps-moat&quot;&gt;Google Maps’ Moat&lt;/a&gt; – Google Maps’ Fascinating, yet scary detail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/war-is-boring/eating-too-much-rice-almost-sank-the-japanese-navy-f985772c81a6&quot;&gt;Eating Too Much Rice Almost Sank the Japanese Navy One doctor’s fight against the nutritional woes of a nation&lt;/a&gt; – the story about one doctor who fight against &lt;em&gt;beriberi&lt;/em&gt; desease that affecting Japanese navy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/charged-tech/apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-mac-is-for-722a2438389b&quot;&gt;Apple just told the world it has no idea who the Mac is for&lt;/a&gt; – an old article, but still reflecting today’s condition, after Macbook Pro with Touchbar came up, the Macbook Pro lineup are not as good as their predecessor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #23</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-23"/>
   <updated>2017-12-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-23</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2016/08/18/nists-new-password-rules-what-you-need-to-know/&quot;&gt;NIST’s new password rules&lt;/a&gt; – an old read, but one of the fine rule how to create password guide for your users.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://coinsutra.com/hodl-popular-cryptocurrency-terms/&quot;&gt;Just HODL!&lt;/a&gt; – couple new lingo from crytocurrencies market, and how the users using it in the chat or forums, some of it hillarious (i have private group to discuss crypto market).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openrailwaymap.org/&quot;&gt;Open Railway Map&lt;/a&gt; – a crowdsourcing data for railway all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #22</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-22"/>
   <updated>2017-12-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-22</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://renderman.pixar.com/stories/cars-3&quot;&gt;Photorealism at Pixar&lt;/a&gt; – i’ve watched the movie, the story is touching and yet somehow the first one is still better on story persfective. this article took us to how cars 3 got made, the images are amazing, attention to details are awesome, it is that good, closer to realistic one, and the holygrail for computer graphics, Photorealism, where you almost can’t tell whether this is a CGI or photo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/55/trust/the-bitcoin-paradox&quot;&gt;Blockchain Explainer&lt;/a&gt; – as previously i’ve mentioned, for the past few days i’m into cryptocurrencies, took a quick lession on how future index where made, and learn couple lingo to familiarizing with index world, it’s not an index, but using the same lingo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2017/12/20/16803190/iphone-slowdown-is-needed-but-also-a-problem&quot;&gt;iPhones start slowing down after a year of use, and that’s way too soon&lt;/a&gt; – this is a bullshit thing from Apple, the reasons behind it are stupid as stupid does.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #21</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-21"/>
   <updated>2017-12-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-21</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/firefox/update-looking-glass-add/?utm_source=dedenf&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&quot;&gt;Mozilla screw things up&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
the internet praising about how Firefox stand with its user, how they were sworn to protect the internet, but screw their users trust by installing add ons without permission, sure there’s an explanation about it, from configuration failure to flawed system, but it still happened, and users did not happy, and this is their apologia regarding that. on the sidenote, Firefox inscreasingly disappointing, the performance are bad, &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/11/firefox-quantum&quot;&gt;not long ago i wrote a praising post&lt;/a&gt; regarding quantum, it even became my primary browser, but now it has go back to where Firefox used to be, sluggish, CPU and RAM eater and put your computer to no use. at first launch it can open 50 tabs with no issue, now i opened 15 tabs and it’s start to slowing down and eventually i have close couple tab or save it on my OneTab extension and opened later.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dwmkerr.com/effective-shell-part-1-navigating-the-command-line/?utm_source=dedenf&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&quot;&gt;Effective Shell&lt;/a&gt; – this is a series of how to use shell effectively, the whole part can be digested even for someone who just know the cli, already watched how Dave worked, indeed, he used the shell effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bigthink.com/scotty-hendricks/10-schools-of-philosophy-and-why-you-should-know-them?utm_source=dedenf&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&quot;&gt;10 school of tought&lt;/a&gt; – list of popular thought, Stoicism are probably important one, in muslim teaching there’s a tought called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_Qonaah_&lt;/code&gt; meaning accepting with we have and keep working.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #20</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-20"/>
   <updated>2017-12-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-20</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stateofjs.com/2017/introduction/&quot;&gt;The State of Javascript 2017&lt;/a&gt; – we’re using quite awful lots of nodejs currently to build Jenius’ microservices, sometimes this thing could be a heaven, but lot of time it’s a pain in the ass. i’m not hating nodejs environment or scene, just can’t stand with the &lt;em&gt;ALL THINGS NEW!&lt;/em&gt; frameworks, again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://woz.posthaven.com/what-orms-have-taught-me-just-learn-sql&quot;&gt;What ORMs have taught me: just learn SQL&lt;/a&gt; – Yes, ORM could save you a lot of time, but it also kills you, you became more and more forgetting how the SQL works, or sometimes you forgot how to do the simple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JOIN&lt;/code&gt; queries. ORM just please use it wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mehdi.cherti.name/improving-my-productivity-using-pomodoro-takeaways-after-2-years-of-practice.html&quot;&gt;Improving productivity – 2 Years practicing Pomodoro&lt;/a&gt; – I use Pomodoro not often, use it when i need to complete task that are time sensitive, for example, writing a blog, or lenghty email. with 25 minutes per session, the words will coming at my fingertip. and sometimes do that when in the development mode, trully efective.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptocurrency&quot;&gt;Cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt; – i’m into this right now, still not serious enough like other, i need to find out how this things are going and how it used in the real world. many choices, and i since i’m in the bank industry right now, blockchain technology will be use in most of the banks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Worst Macbook Pro Ever</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/worst-macbookpro"/>
   <updated>2017-12-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/worst-macbookpro</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a rant, Macbook Pro with touchbar are the worst macbook pro ever created by Apple, probably in all the line up of the macbooks, let me break it down, i’ve been using Apple for quite some time, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://everymac.com/systems/apple/macbook/specs/macbook_1.83.html&quot;&gt;white macbook&lt;/a&gt; is the first macbook i ever bought, didn’t have chance (&lt;em&gt;read&lt;/em&gt;: cannot afford) to buy Powerbook earlier. and this time i’m using Macbook Pro with touchbar (late 2016), and it’s a disappointment, yes, couple feature that i loved like its keyboard, it is good, and it was light, comparing to other macbook pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of it overshadowed by its performance battery and overall speed, the battery life is suck, 3 hour active usage is never achieved, 2.5 hours top, even if you were just browsing around, no video streaming, it still suck up your battery life, the auto contrast stupid as hell. and if you are a developer, you are fucked, you can’t have multiple virtual host or docker running without sacrificing the battery life, i have try to run full blown devs env, and it was run just almost 2 hour on battery. and no, i’m not using just one macbook pro with touchbar, i have tried 3 of them, and still have the same result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just, wtf Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #19</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-19"/>
   <updated>2017-12-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-19</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2017-12-14/2017-was-bad-for-facebook-2018-will-be-worse&quot;&gt;2017 was bad for facebook, 2018 Will Be Worse.&lt;/a&gt; – i’ve quit Facebook since 4 years ago, but have to admit that social media are still the place where you can see or feel connected to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shirky.com/weblog/2010/04/the-collapse-of-complex-business-models/&quot;&gt;The Collapse of Complex Business Models&lt;/a&gt; – Interesting essay, and i suppose the ancient cities that spans accross Europe for example, reach its peak, and crumble, dunno whether it because of how they manage the country or just simply decided to abandon everything.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #18</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-18"/>
   <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/dailybite-18</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jrnl.sh/&quot;&gt;Jrnl&lt;/a&gt; – is a dead simple journal app, a lot of fancy journal out there like Evernote, DayOne, and newer journal also with rich editing – Bear app. Jrnl.sh is simple, it runs on command line, no hassle, the configs are quite straigt forward, it also support for encryption. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jrnl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/articles/products-over-projects.html&quot;&gt;Products over projects&lt;/a&gt; – quite long essay, worth to read to examine your products development over the whole projects.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backerkit.com/blog/distributed-teams&quot;&gt;Distributed Teams&lt;/a&gt; – the key for distributed team, small or large, still on the communications, if it hard to communicating in the same floor, don’t try to do remote.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chill&quot;&gt;Chill&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my current playlist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/embed/user/spotify/playlist/37i9dQZF1DX6ziVCJnEm59&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gunung Agung</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/gunung-agung"/>
   <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/gunung-agung</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a highest mountain in the island of Bali, as high as 3031m above the sea level, and sunday morning, it was erupted, sending ashes, and sometimes stone, it is not severe, but still, it has a huge effect on surrounding, like people have to be evacuated because the ashes is quite thick. According to our driver, his house were 7km from Mt Agung, the ashes is like 1cm thick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, flight cancelation, many people could not back to their country/places, i was on of them, my flight should be on Tuesday 23.40, but because the mountain status is not that flight friendly, so we took decision to came back at monday to Jakarta, this time using SUB as our departure, and we have to take a road for like 13 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/maps-bali-juanda.png&quot; alt=&quot;bali to juanda airport&quot; /&gt;
It was quite a ride, as you can see on the map, it took us around 13 hours to get to Juanda Airport, and the Surabaya toll is not friendly IMHO, Porong still flooded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is was a gem, it was a thrilling experieces, we get to know further north of Bali, we passed Yeh Leh beach, which was awesome, beach and rice paddy get a long together, and further west we can see mountains, it was gorgeous.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/yehleh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yehleh&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;the beach photos are blurry, rice paddy much better, &lt;i&gt;Location: Jembrana.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we get some rest before the Gilimanuk ferry port, we have our lunch-ish at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.co.id/Restaurant_Review-g1592983-d4799827-Reviews-Ayam_Betutu_Men_Tempeh-Gilimanuk_Bali.html&quot;&gt;Ayam Betutu Men Tempeh&lt;/a&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/VtC5HPUPUzR2&quot;&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;), it was the best chicken i ever had, it was soft, warm, very nice flavor. &lt;br /&gt;
One thing i noticed at Gilimanuk area, there’s a mosque, Masjid besar Al-Mubarok, and not from there, there’s a little &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Balinese_temple&quot;&gt;Pura&lt;/a&gt;, i loved to see them side by side, there’s no hatred, just minding their own business (or god), it should be like that. no one forcing each other, or hating each other because of their belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Gilimanuk port, we were registered at the counter at the entrance, if i’m not mistaken, it was 140K IDR for a private car, and inside, we were queueing to get to the ferry. on this stage, i think need skilled driver to park the car in the ferry, backward. luckily our car is the last one who enter the ferry (so we could be first when unload). 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/loading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loading&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;final loading and off we go!&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;like i said, it was a gem, mount Agung may erupted, but we have new experience, new adventure, never been using a ferry to cross from Bali, and the view are awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/ferry.mp4&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;i&gt;chillin'&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;couple of picture i took a long the way.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/bali-juanda/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #17</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-17"/>
   <updated>2017-11-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-17</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thankyouopensource.com/&quot;&gt;Thank you Opensource project letter&lt;/a&gt; – It’s a way to say thank you to Opensource creator/contributor, people can say gratitude to their favorite Opensource project, and sometimes the letter are quite hillarious.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html&quot;&gt;A CEO’s Guide to Emacs&lt;/a&gt; – Even tho i’m not a CEO or using EMACs intensively, this is a quite comprehensive reading, Emacs can be use with other thing, some people integrate it with mp3/Spotify, and other things that i cannot imagined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wexnermedical.osu.edu/brain-spine-neuro/memory-disorders/sage&quot;&gt;SAGE: A Test to Detect Signs of Alzheimer’s and Dementia&lt;/a&gt; – Self-Administered Gerocognitive Exam, I remember my grandmother had this Alzheimer, this simple testing could analyze and do some simple evaluation (you still nedd to go to the doctor for further evalution).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>MoMA : Shipping and Receiving</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/MoMa"/>
   <updated>2017-11-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/MoMa</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mG6mYhEGMXs?rel=0&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cool video showed The Museum of Modern Art, what they do, what the prepared, in the video, there’s no cinematic or some hipster sound as background, and not even narrator to explain the whole thing, just raw situation and ambience of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moma.org/&quot;&gt;MoMA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #16</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-16"/>
   <updated>2017-11-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-16</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prweek.com/article/1450698/lego-learned-building-social-network-kids&quot;&gt;What Lego has learned from building social network for kids&lt;/a&gt; – It is amazing to see how a marketing platform to become a thing that every kids that play lego waiting, in that platform, kids around the world show case their ingenuity crafting Lego, i am fond of Lego.
The experience that this team had was how they capture what their customer wants by using data, this data led development or mapping the roadmap put their priorities sorted out.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“We used to &lt;strong&gt;focus on one part of data and that would become the truth&lt;/strong&gt;. Everything would be based on that one fact and it would lead development. That does not work. &lt;strong&gt;To be data led, you have to look at small things&lt;/strong&gt;, like the number of kids that fell out of a flow, or what’s affecting sign-ups,”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/run-the-first-edition-of-unix-1972-with-docker&quot;&gt;Run the First Edition of Unix (1972) with Docker&lt;/a&gt; – i may not yet born that time of the year, even play with it, my oldest memory at my first interaction with computer was &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Personal_Computer_XT&quot;&gt;IBM XT&lt;/a&gt;. my brother who were showed me how the Lotus works, with PC-DOS 2 (or 3 i forgot).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #15</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-15"/>
   <updated>2017-11-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-15</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2017/11/entering-the-quantum-era-how-firefox-got-fast-again-and-where-its-going-to-get-faster/&quot;&gt;Entering the Quantum Era—How Firefox got fast again and where it’s going to get faster&lt;/a&gt; – I’ve been reviewing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.dedenf.com/2017/11/firefox-quantum&quot;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; earlier, this is a much more fun way to ilustrate the new technologies behind new Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://security.googleblog.com/2017/11/new-research-understanding-root-cause.html&quot;&gt;New research: Understanding the root cause of account takeover&lt;/a&gt; – The paper published here by &lt;a href=&quot;https://static.googleusercontent.com/media/research.google.com/en//pubs/archive/46437.pdf&quot;&gt;Google Research Paper&lt;/a&gt;, the paper showed the breach from various site, and also how it was sold in black market, &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3devm/motherboard-guide-to-not-getting-hacked-online-safety-guide&quot;&gt;motherboard wrote a how to not get hacked guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #14</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-14"/>
   <updated>2017-11-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-14</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-talk-about-sleep&quot;&gt;Let’s Talk about sleep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i’ve been talking about sleep deprivation on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.dedenf.com/2017/11/dailybite-8?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;dailybite issue #8&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/sleep-deprivation-epidemic-health-effects-tired-heart-disease-stroke-dementia-cancer-a7964156.html?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;how it affect how we live&lt;/a&gt;, and society is changing, with all the gadgets, nightlife, always-on, fomo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Electric lights, television and computer screens, longer commutes, the blurring of the line between work and personal time, and a host of other aspects of modern life have contributed to sleep deprivation, which is defined as less than seven hours a night. &lt;br /&gt;
But this has been linked to cancer, diabetes, heart disease, stroke, Alzheimer’s disease, obesity and poor mental health among other health problems. In short, a lack of sleep is killing us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other experiment also proving the same thing about the impact of sleep deprivation, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bigthink.com/philip-perry/how-sleep-deprivation-leads-to-mental-sluggishness?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;mental sluggishness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The sleep deprived have a higher risk of quite a number of conditions including heart disease, hypertension, type 2 diabetes, obesity, and depression. Lack of sleep also has a deleterious effect on the brain, particularly on memory and cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is much more scarier, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/how-much-sleep-is-enough-health-risks-dangers-of-sleep-deprivation-2017-11/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;Sleep debt is carcinogenic&lt;/a&gt;, watch the video &lt;a href=&quot;https://content.jwplatform.com/players/GNX7U2Wq-puACk8ZV.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2017/01/how-to-sleep/508781/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;healthy sleep&lt;/a&gt;, that’s what we need, according that article, women need at least 7.63 hours of sleep, and men 7.76 hours of sleep, so there’s no hack for long we can stay awake without disturbing our sleep behaviour, and no, you cannot take some drugs as a replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #13</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-13"/>
   <updated>2017-11-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-13</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alexpetralia.com/posts/2017/6/26/learning-linux-bash-to-get-things-done&quot;&gt;Learn just enough Linux to get things done&lt;/a&gt; – I remember learn how to install and operate Linux and Novel at 1999, and that was 18 years ago. been thru quite a lot linux flavour, learn how to use shell, bash is the most used shell interface, and then learn how to configure the network, thin client configuration, and so on. and eventually working as a part time admin at &lt;em&gt;warnet&lt;/em&gt; (basically an internet cafe), these skills surely acquired and used a long with my career on the development area.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theintercept.com/2017/11/06/how-twitter-secretly-benefits-from-bots-and-fake-accounts/&quot;&gt;How Twitter Secretly Benefits From Bots and Fake Accounts&lt;/a&gt; – US election changes so many things, beside Twitter approach is quite disturbing, i still use Twitter sometimes to catch updates from couple account that i follow. but this report happened on almost industries, e-commerce are one of the industry that using this tactic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #12</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-12"/>
   <updated>2017-11-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-12</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another friday, have we all reflect on what we have done over the weekdays?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/veteran-cto-with-20-years-experience-answers-your-top-startup-building-questions/?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;Veteran CTO (with Multiple Successful Exits) Answers Your Top Startup-Building Questions&lt;/a&gt; – 
Many advice for an inspiring tech managers, the list and experience by Adil Ajmal are gold, how the engineer accept its roles, and how they become a team player. Mesuring projects, performances, so on. and i’m quite intrigued by this:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I believe that architecting a system is the responsibility of all engineers who have to build and maintain that system and not the exclusive responsibility of a single individual or a team of individuals who just tell others what to do without actually building the system themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/move-slowly-and-fix-things-e5a560fd928b?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;Move Slowly and Fix Things&lt;/a&gt; – I do love this approach, do with small thing, fix that small thing, look upon what’s coming, iterate. i tried to keep things small, functional, add some stuff slowly and iterate to be better.
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;But now most software is so much more than that. It listens to us. It goes everywhere we go. It tracks everything we do. It has our fingerprints. Our heart rate. Our money. Our location. Our face. It’s the primary way we communicate our thoughts and feelings to our friends and family. &lt;br /&gt;
It’s deeply personal and ingrained into every aspect of our lives. It commands our gaze more and more every day.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/d3devm/motherboard-guide-to-not-getting-hacked-online-safety-guide?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;The Motherboard Guide to Not Getting Hacked&lt;/a&gt; – a comprehensive guide for not getting hacked. but all the tools for security always falls down to how the user treat their data. people tend to share almost everything on the internet, and hoping what they do won’t have consequence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #11</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/2dailybite-11"/>
   <updated>2017-11-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/2dailybite-11</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.class-central.com/&quot;&gt;Course Central&lt;/a&gt; – Free online course from 200 top universities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://moviesbyminutes.com/&quot;&gt;Movies by Minutes&lt;/a&gt; – A Podcast that will discuss popular movies, minute by minute.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IBM/type&quot;&gt;Type by IBM&lt;/a&gt; – IBM new typeface, and how IBM &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1124664/ibm-plex-with-its-first-ever-custom-corporate-font-ibm-is-freeing-itself-from-the-tyranny-of-helvetica/&quot;&gt;freeing itself from helvetica&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xcs9snQnkJs&amp;amp;amp=&amp;amp;app=desktop&quot;&gt;watch the video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/11/20/how-to-get-rich-playing-video-games-online&quot;&gt;How to Get Rich Playing Video Games Online&lt;/a&gt; – Online streamer service especially gamers has became a source of income, and it also affect other kind of video creator, like youtuber, this also has become a career path for some people, Indonesia one of it, many kids who were dreaming to become a youtuber, a badge that they can carry and they think that it will have a lot of money out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mainframe Kid</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/1mainframe-kid"/>
   <updated>2017-11-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/1mainframe-kid</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Loved this video, it’s just about a kid, who build his own mainframe, a normal kid would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wJyiHsfJLEI?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Firefox Quantum</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/firefox-quantum"/>
   <updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/firefox-quantum</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/firefox-quantum/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;firefox quantum&quot; /&gt;
Recently Firefox launched its new version of Firefox, dubbed Firefox Quantum, it promised a lot of improvements from previous version. according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&quot;&gt;release post&lt;/a&gt;, it was built using new core engine to render page, and also new UI &lt;a href=&quot;http://design.firefox.com/photon/welcome.html&quot;&gt;design&lt;/a&gt;, it also promised less memory consumption. &lt;br /&gt;
Few things i want to highlight from this new release.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;search&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new search design also compelling, it displayed multiple search engine as you go, and you can switch between search engine easily.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/firefox-quantum/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;search engine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;addons-management&quot;&gt;Addons Management&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there’s no radical change from this feature compared with the old one, but this UI look and feel a bit fresh.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/firefox-quantum/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Addons Management&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;customize-firefox&quot;&gt;Customize Firefox&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature has been redesigned also, and also looks fresh. i love it.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/firefox-quantum/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Customize Firefox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new release, Firefox Quantum has been proven fast!, i love it, yes it uses purely 64bit, new design, i like it, just need to get used to with black bar (yes you can customize it, but still..), in the Chrome world it is an Incognito mode. the syncing account works fine. Probably this is the right time to come back using it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #10</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite10"/>
   <updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite10</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/mjs538/i-followed-my-stolen-iphone-across-the-world-became-a-celebr?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;I Followed My Stolen iPhone Across The World, Became A Celebrity In China, And Found A Friend For Life&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 this is an old post, but still amazing to read, how this guy lost his iPhone, and that iPhone somehow ended up in China, he already set up his iCould, and the guy who bought the iPhone’s photos always sent out to iCould. the journey is hillarious and simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2017/apple-at-its-best/&quot;&gt;Apple at its best&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 The latest flagship from Apple, iPhone X (ten!) still a thing that people [need|want] to buy, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J5etXw2ngaE&quot;&gt;people still lining up to buy one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ici.radio-canada.ca/special/sextorsion/en/index.html&quot;&gt;Inside the fake Facebook profile industry&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 Luring people to add someone else and ‘like-farming’ activity are not a secret in Facebook world. There’s a network of fake profile and then sell it when it got famous on black market.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #9</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/2dailybite-9"/>
   <updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/2dailybite-9</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss&quot;&gt;The Case For RSS&lt;/a&gt; – i’ve put up the comment on this &lt;a href=&quot;http://notes.dedenf.com/2017/11/1on-rss&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athityakumar/colorls&quot;&gt;Colorls&lt;/a&gt; – it’s an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; with color!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/11/14/introducing-firefox-quantum/&quot;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; – I guess it is fast! &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/n6wiRyKkmKc&quot;&gt;Firefox Quantum&lt;/a&gt; kinda Chrome-ish, but it is better than previous version.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About RSS</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/1on-rss"/>
   <updated>2017-11-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/1on-rss</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the my rss feed source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/11/the-case-for-rss?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about how he still using RSS as a main source of information, and i’m fully agree with it, i’m a fan of RSS, i can’t replace it with social media like Twitter, following news outlet to get some news, or any other social media platform, i still use the old plain RSS (regardless its an xml feed or json feed), using the social media as a source can be distracting, you could ended up reading many post unrelated to your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is so much easier to look upon, maintain and follow. yes, you could ended up with a lot of ‘dirty’ things filled on your reader, but the key is you have to selectively choose the feed that you like, and make sure the quality of the post itself. i will not for example subscribe to news site like Detik.com or Kompas.com, it’s a suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For RSS reader i’m using &lt;a href=&quot;http://cappuccinoapp.com/?ref=dedenf&quot;&gt;Cappuccino&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a beta for now, and good thing it’s free, i’m using Feedly for a while, but i came back to Cappuccino.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/cappuccino.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cappuccino&quot; /&gt;
all my feed could be grabbed on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dedenf/news-feed&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #8</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-8"/>
   <updated>2017-11-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/dailybite-8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Being busy is a good thing, but the progress of this dailybites deprioritized, hate to see that, now, i’m trying to keep up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.independent.co.uk/news/sleep-deprivation-epidemic-health-effects-tired-heart-disease-stroke-dementia-cancer-a7964156.html&quot;&gt;‘Catastrophic’ lack of sleep in modern society is killing us, warns leading sleep scientist&lt;/a&gt; – this is so true in may ways, there are still developers who were bragging this habbit, lack of sleep is not a bragging rights, it’s a downright productivities, and how can four or five hours’ sleep a night can triggered cancer cell.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2017#overview&quot;&gt;Developer Survey Results 2017&lt;/a&gt; – I love the way STO present these kinda thing. i’m focusing on technologies, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Javascript&lt;/code&gt; is the most popular language that lots of people use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/toddmotto/public-apis&quot;&gt;A collective list of free APIs for use in web development.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
quite a comprehensive list of all things APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #7</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-7"/>
   <updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-7</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2017/10/24/theicon&quot;&gt;The Icon Journey&lt;/a&gt; – The icon journey of Visual Studio Code, how its being made and how the initial design since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://experiments.withgoogle.com/ai/&quot;&gt;Google AI Experiment&lt;/a&gt; – Fun!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/&quot;&gt;Tufte CSS&lt;/a&gt; – I kinda like this CSS, tempting to revamp my blog (again) using this, i always love the style with heavy texts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/what-habits-made-me-a-better-software-engineer-47e7d54b8fa&quot;&gt;What habits made me a better Software Engineer?&lt;/a&gt; – every developers has their own approach to become better (better is so subjective btw), but from these list, a lot of point spot on, and i want to point out how important writing blogs or article is (i try to do that to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jenius.tech&quot;&gt;developers&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jenius.com&quot;&gt;Jenius&lt;/a&gt; ), it is so helpful and also makes you a good storyteller.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #6</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/02-daily-bite-6"/>
   <updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/02-daily-bite-6</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://landing.google.com/sre/book.html&quot;&gt;Site Reliability Engineering – The Book&lt;/a&gt; – Freely available, you can read it online or buy hard copy. this is absolute gems for my team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@deusexmachina667/you-fired-your-top-talent-i-hope-youre-happy-cf57c41183dd&quot;&gt;You fired your top talent. I hope you’re happy.&lt;/a&gt; – it is basically a shout out to previous article (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/we-fired-our-top-talent-best-decision-we-ever-made-4c0a99728fde?gi=fbc062e62a4&quot;&gt;read here first&lt;/a&gt;), all argument on both article could be right, i have seen both of the case, from the developer itself and from the company who were don’t give a damn to the developers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/taika-waititi-thor-ragnarok-profile&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thor: Ragnarok’s&lt;/em&gt; Taika Waititi Is Here to Save the Blockbuster&lt;/a&gt; – it’s a fun movie btw, but not much i can remember, it’s just many laughter, funny character, after watch it, it’s just… gone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Flash</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/01-the-flash"/>
   <updated>2017-11-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/01-the-flash</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/flash-run.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the flash run! but damaging the stairs&quot; /&gt;
As one of the flash’ fans, not a hardcore fans, but enjoying the mythology. and been a loyal audience for the flash series. but still sometime it irritated me to see how Flash potrayed, on the series (the old one and new), the most irritating one is well his speed (i’m talking about Barry Allen’s flash, yeah there’s a lot of Flashs), Flash should be faster than anyone, even Reverse Flash could travel time/universe while having conversation with himself to decieved anyone that they were different person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somehow, the flash, when he ran, there’s lightning and glasses shattered when he run, this is annoying, since he is the fastest man alive, and according &lt;a href=&quot;https://comicvine.gamespot.com/barry-allen/4005-22804/forums/flash-max-speed-704188/&quot;&gt;this fans calculation&lt;/a&gt;, he can run 9,400,000 million times the speed of light, so basically, he is invinsible, and with that speed, he could fly and after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r9-DM9uBtVI&quot;&gt;Justice league final trailer&lt;/a&gt;, again, disappointed, the surface is breaking while he ran and almost all of the villian can see flash run (see above screencap), why?.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he just ordinary fast, not as much as 9.400.000 million the speed of light and i’m being too serious, where’s my coffee?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #5</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-5"/>
   <updated>2017-11-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-5</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.kinja-img.com/gawker-media/image/upload/aoxjg0jeh5zeg424uyy6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whale Whisperers. Credit: Anuar Patjane Floriuk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sploid.gizmodo.com/this-years-best-press-photos-are-absolutely-electrifyin-1759894233?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;This Year’s Best Press Photos Are Absolutely Electrifying&lt;/a&gt; – i love these photos, especially Whale Whisperer (above).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zwischenzugs.com/2017/10/27/ten-things-i-wish-id-known-before-using-vagrant/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;Ten Things I Wish I’d Known Before Using Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; – i use Vagrant almost all the time, for openshift development and whole bunch of things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pamelafox/my-morning-practice-40ec0887a260?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;My Morning Practice&lt;/a&gt; – i don’t have one, beside waking up (sometimes late), i should start one &lt;em&gt;tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #4</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-4"/>
   <updated>2017-11-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-4</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2017/11/why-do-we-still-commute/544733/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;The Economics of the Office: Why Do We Still Commute?&lt;/a&gt; – Some people said that commuting is a waste of time. money, and productivity. but some people love it, as a routine, it’s a constant thing that they love.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.percona.com/blog/2017/11/02/mysql-vs-mariadb-reality-check/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;MySQL vs. MariaDB: Reality Check&lt;/a&gt; – Comparison head to head between the two (and Percona’s own mysql release).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://m.signalvnoise.com/how-do-you-focus-cbc3d6d78463?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;How Do You Focus?&lt;/a&gt; – how can we focus, with all the disturbance, things that was goig on, things that you have to do sometime at the same time. but priority is important, but hei, i’m watching Stranger Things season 2 while writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenextweb-com.cdn.ampproject.org/c/s/thenextweb.com/artificial-intelligence/2017/10/25/airbnb-ai-sketches-design-code/?amp=1?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;Airbnb built an AI that turns design sketches into product source code&lt;/a&gt; – aah ho00mans&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #3</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-3"/>
   <updated>2017-11-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://frontendmasters.com/books/front-end-handbook/2017/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;Front-End Developer Handbook 2017&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Front-end development becoming really complicated these day, from just simple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; and just hard link to a file, we still do that, but the effort is quite expensive, this is a great compilation about how Front-end got implemented, and couple things that have to be know by Front-End.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/invision-marvel-justinmind-prototyping-tools-compared/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;15 Top Prototyping Tools Go Head-to-Head&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Head to head comparison of prototyping tools, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jenius.com&quot;&gt;jenius&lt;/a&gt; we use Adobe XD, Zeplin and Sketch. all of them powered our design team.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/stevedenning/2017/10/15/what-is-agile-the-four-essential-elements/amp/&quot;&gt;Four Essential Elements of Agile&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
We know that this Agile is a thing now, many company declared that they were agile, for me agile is about adapting, how can we adapt into technology, culture and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Bite&lt;/strong&gt; is a series to documenting of what i followed and read during the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #2</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-2"/>
   <updated>2017-11-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/daily-bite-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hpe.com/us/en/insights/articles/the-owasp-top-10-is-killing-me-and-killing-you-1710.html&quot;&gt;The OWASP Top 10 is killing me, and killing you!&lt;/a&gt; – 
Another laundry list&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2015/12/30/paris-syndrome-culture-shock-sickness-sends-japanese-tourists-packing&quot;&gt;Paris Syndrome: culture shock sickness sends Japanese tourists packing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Non-techie article, and a bit old, and quite frankly, a lot of people having the same issue, the real world is not what they expected to be. people saw it on photos/video/movie and hopping the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-node-js-collection/news-node-js-8-moves-into-long-term-support-and-node-js-9-becomes-the-new-current-release-line-74cf754a10a0&quot;&gt;Node 8 Moves into Long-Term Support and Node 9 is the current release&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Truth is, i’m a bit skeptical and confused sometimes about Node life cycle, and between major release don’t know how many APIs that gonna be broken.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daily Bite #1</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/daily-bite-1"/>
   <updated>2017-10-31T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/daily-bite-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first edition of Daily Bite, i’m trying to read, learn and observe on the development/technology/life/etc and get some insight of it as i can, i already have post couple post using reading list subject, and this time will try to publish it on daily basis (tentative on weekend).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alexhudson.com/2017/10/14/software-architecture-failing/?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;Software architecture is failing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Interesting read, and in fact reflects to at least my professional life, the over-designed and over-architecture system that sometimes hurting the delivery, not to mention the business. the point to make in my opinion is as developer we should be wise and also thoughful using all the hyped or cool kids technologies&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/how-awesome-engineers-ask-for-help-93bcb2c7dbb7?utm_source=dedenf&quot;&gt;How awesome engineers ask for help&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Communication is the key in development word, communication can be anywhere and using any tools that we have, slack, telegram, whatsapp, or even in the codes, how we connect with other developer and so, but sometimes ego will kill it all, the attitude like i’m the best, i don’t need help from the other. remember there are human behind the code that we wrote, human who make it all possible, your colleague, your open source tools that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/10/18/15995478/chocolate-health-benefits-heart-disease&quot;&gt;Dark chocolate is now a health food&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
My wife would love this, the chocolate that we know right now for example from cadburry, kitkat or lindt, etc. are not pure chocolate, the main ingredient are mostly sugar and fat. but dark chocolate is different, i love dark chocolate, much more tasteful and now it is officially healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://devdocs.io/&quot;&gt;Devdocs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This is pure gold, remember when you have to visit all the docs site to get sense what are these function do, now we have it in one place.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>High Sierra</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/high-sierra"/>
   <updated>2017-09-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/high-sierra</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/high-sierra.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upgraded to latest Apple macOS High Sierra, i think i love it, and i think this is the first time i upgraded the system without waiting x.x.1 (10.12.1 for example). couple thing that i considered as things i hate, digital clock (now with dot, e.g 10.12), how it displayed the size of the file or transfer (now with comma, e.g &lt;em&gt;Transfering 10,3MB&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couple review from other site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/09/macos-10-13-high-sierra-the-ars-technica-review/&quot;&gt;macOS 10.13 High Sierra: The Ars Technica review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/9/25/16352736/macos-high-sierra-review-safari-autoplay-blocking&quot;&gt;There’s one good reason to update to macOS High Sierra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/09/25/macos-high-sierra-is-an-infrastructural-update/&quot;&gt;macOS High Sierra’s biggest updates happen behind the scenes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trustedreviews.com/reviews/apple-macos-high-sierra&quot;&gt;Apple macOS High Sierra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update 3 October 2017&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
since i’m using Macbook Pro with touchbar, i can’t swipe between desktop, sometimes it broken, don’t know whether it’s related, it has different trackpad, checked my uptime and it says only 7 days up, bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Acquired Taste</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/acquired-taste"/>
   <updated>2017-09-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/acquired-taste</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever have a thing that used to be you dislike and from time to time you were changed and began to like the thing that you dislike? maybe by experiece, by how we approach things differently, or you just forced it and become a habit and it suddenly less sucks than it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be dislike coffee without sugar, it’s bitter, nothing else, but through out the time, i began to enjoy coffee without sugar after couple of time tasting it, and also using different approach of how i tasted the coffee, buying couple coffee brewing tools and different varieties of coffee, single origin or blend, or whatever. bought a domain name for my love for coffee (&lt;a href=&quot;http://epicoffee.com&quot;&gt;http://epicoffee.com&lt;/a&gt;), this thing also happened to Guinness, Wine.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sierra Mail App</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/mail-app"/>
   <updated>2017-07-26T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/mail-app</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I Have been tried many mail client for my work email (Polymail, Spark, Outlook(!), etc), and as we all know, corporate web based email is ugly, from Zimbra to Microsoft Outlook, some might tried to make it look nicer, but still i prefer using a desktop app for my everyday mailing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love macOS mail app, but up until Sierra released, the Mail app change, the one thing that annoyed me is, i cannot see the recipients list unless i clicked the ‘&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;’ menu. it used to be clicking the ‘&lt;strong&gt;&amp;amp; 10 more&lt;/strong&gt;’ if you have more than 2 cc for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/hate-this-feature.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;why&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the only thing i complained about Spark is, it cannot send email with email as an attachments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;time class=&quot;updated&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-11-06T10:33:52+07:00&quot; pubdate=&quot;&quot;&gt;6 November 2017&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: On macOS High Sierra, this issue has been fixed, and the old behavior has been restored, &lt;em&gt;Yeayyy!&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LEGO&reg;: Customer service done right</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/customer-service-lego"/>
   <updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/customer-service-lego</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So the story began when my nephew had his Lego brick piece is missing, it’s new, and he was trying to search the piece, probably hiding somewhere in the box, with no luck. And cleverly decided to email Lego support, tell them that he had not recieve a full pieces of his Lego, and the response from Lego is astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lego-custserving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lego letter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s customer satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>USB Type-C</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/usb-type-c"/>
   <updated>2017-07-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/usb-type-c</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacBook_Pro#Fourth_generation_.28Touch_Bar.29&quot;&gt;Macbook Pro&lt;/a&gt; that equipped with USB Type-c is quite challenging, not because it’s bad, but this USB type is ‘unconventional’, means, it’s hard to connect your peripherals because all you have is USB Type-A connectors, buying an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MJ1M2AM/A/usb-c-to-usb-adapter&quot;&gt;Apple USB-C to USB converter&lt;/a&gt; seems ridiculously pricey, and this is a review-ish kinda thing.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Enter &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USB_On-The-Go&quot;&gt;OTG&lt;/a&gt; (On The Go), and i bought an OTG device branded REMAX, i use the USB-C to USB-A type, it works, it can connect my mouse, external harddrive, iPhone, and other peripherals. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/usbc-connected.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;in action&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it converting to USB 3.0 port, the speed is quite decend, the device benchmarked using &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/blackmagic-disk-speed-test/id425264550?mt=12&quot;&gt;Blackmagic Disk Speed Test&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xbench.com/&quot;&gt;Xbench&lt;/a&gt;, and it shows a decend speed, in terms of read and write.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/usbc-diskspeedtest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blackmagic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/usbc-xbench.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Xbench&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All and all, using the new device with ALL port using USB-C is quite cumbersome if you are using a lot of peripherals USB-A that needed to be connected.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How the iPhone Was Born: Inside Stories of Missteps and Triumphs</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/links"/>
   <updated>2017-07-04T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/links</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;How Apple build and success with the iPhone, couple former VPs on the interview, it’s a great video!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/video/living-with-the-original-iphone-in-2017/790062D5-748C-47CE-A515-549D1C03E6F3.html&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hooverphonic</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/hooverphonic"/>
   <updated>2017-06-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/hooverphonic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Don’t know where i have been, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLbsgOyRLYNfZk-7fJE7iXt26_Y6888B36&quot;&gt;these Hooverphonic concert&lt;/a&gt; with an orchestra is AMAZING!, the symfony, vocals, everything, it’s just perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was first introduced with triphop songs by my late-friend Taufik (GBU my friend), he introduced me to the type of Portishead, Hooverphonic, Lamb, Goldfrapp, etc. i was hooked, need more, just listening to a cassette (it’s year 2000 after all), mp3 is just booming, file sharing is everywhere (napster, kazaa, – &lt;em&gt;yeah old&lt;/em&gt;), and i admit it that i was using that service a while back just to get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZJSQxbedplM&quot;&gt;2Wicky&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6EA-MIYY1bg&quot;&gt;Mad About You&lt;/a&gt; from Hooverphonic in MP3 format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6EA-MIYY1bg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Sociology of the Smartphone</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/reading-list"/>
   <updated>2017-06-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/reading-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a quite long essay, things are spot on, it tells how smartphones changes our lives, our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For many of us, they are the last thing we look at before sleep each night, and the first thing we reach for upon waking. We use them to meet people, to communicate, to entertain ourselves, and to find our way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;those line almost summed up our daily activity, and how smartphone integral part to our lives, read it all, it is worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;another-read&quot;&gt;Another read&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-you-should-manage-your-energy-not-your-time-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20170612-why-you-should-manage-your-energy-not-your-time&quot;&gt;Why you should manage your energy, not your time →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;leaving-social-media-taught-me-how-broken-the-news-cycle-is-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/leaving-social-media-taught-me-how-broken-the-news-cycle-is&quot;&gt;Leaving Social Media Taught Me How Broken The News Cycle Is →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A day with Safari</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/a-day-with-safari"/>
   <updated>2017-06-13T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/a-day-with-safari</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently i’m trying to use Safari more than before, this idea coming because using Chrome is pain in the ass in terms of resources, and by simple thought, probably if i use Safari as a default browser it could dramatically change how my browsing experience and also its resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still use El Capitan macOS, i hate Sierra, the iCloud integration seems annoying (i do have other backup strategy tho), i’ve installed Sierra on my other macs, and regretting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And using Safari (on El Capitan) did not improve my browsing experience, and sometimes the page did not loaded perfectly, probably the site, but &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; on Chrome it is smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/safari.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/safari.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/chrome.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/chrome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see the top menu position?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;probably if high Sierra released, i’ll give it a try its Safari, according to WWDC, it has tons of improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jenius x JVMUG - Reactive System</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/jvm-jenius-reactive-system"/>
   <updated>2017-05-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/jvm-jenius-reactive-system</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm x Jenius&quot; /&gt;
Team Jenius dan komunitas JVM user group mengadakan event meetup dengan topik mengenai &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reactive System&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, topik ini sangat menarik karena membahas ide fundamental dari bagaimana membangun system yang &lt;em&gt;robust&lt;/em&gt; dan tentu saja &lt;em&gt;scaled&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Reactive System&lt;/em&gt; sendiri merupakan satu cara untuk membangun arsitektural sistem yang memungkin aplikasi-aplikasi atau servis-servis yang tersebar menjadi semacam satu unit, bereaksi ke sistem yang ada di sekelilingnya, dan &lt;em&gt;aware&lt;/em&gt; terhadap satu sistem dengan lainnya.
&lt;em&gt;Meetup&lt;/em&gt; ini menghadirkan pembicara &lt;strong&gt;Eko Kurniawan&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Principal Engineer&lt;/em&gt; dari &lt;strong&gt;blibli.com&lt;/strong&gt; dan &lt;strong&gt;Andi Pangeran&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Senior Software Engineer&lt;/em&gt; dari &lt;strong&gt;jurnal.id&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jenius.com&quot;&gt;Jenius&lt;/a&gt; akan selalu mengadakan event-event yang bisa digunakan untuk komunitas (tidak terbatas &lt;em&gt;tech&lt;/em&gt;), selain untuk menambah pengetahuan, kultur &lt;em&gt;engineering&lt;/em&gt; di Jenius dan juga bermanfaat bagi komunitas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;photo dari &lt;em&gt;meetup&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-0-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm x Jenius&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-1-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm x Jenius&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-2-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm x Jenius&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-3-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvm2/jvm2-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm x Jenius&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS&lt;/em&gt;, kalau ada yang tertarik mengadakan event di Jenius, silakan kontak di deden@jenius.com&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Take a moment</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/hero-not-deserved"/>
   <updated>2017-05-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/hero-not-deserved</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/hero-not-deserved.png&quot; alt=&quot;hero does not deserved&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/ht @inasaf&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jenius x JVM User Group meetup</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/jvm-meetup"/>
   <updated>2017-05-04T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/jvm-meetup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On May 3rd, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenius.com&quot;&gt;Jenius&lt;/a&gt; with JVMUserGroup community held an event, it’s a developer’s event, since its JVM (taken from Java Virtual Machine), it discussed couple new technology that happened on the Java world, the subject is “&lt;strong&gt;Microservice mudah dan cepat dengan Spring Boot&lt;/strong&gt;”.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Since Spring is one of the popular java framework on earth, and when it mentioned about the easiness of how this Spring framework advantage, and how it can be used as microservices. &lt;br /&gt;
here are few photos on the meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvmusergroup/jvm1.png&quot; alt=&quot;jvm meetup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvmusergroup/jvm2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm meetup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jvmusergroup/jvm3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;jvm meetup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;make sure you join their telegram group @JVMUsergroup, and we are planning to do the next meetup again with JVMUsergroup, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenius.com&quot;&gt;Jenius&lt;/a&gt; floor about reactive programming. thanks for all participant and organizer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ode For Wujudkan.com</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/an-ode-wujudkan"/>
   <updated>2017-03-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/an-ode-wujudkan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;spoiler&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wujudkan.com&quot;&gt;wujudkan.com&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wujudkan.com/2017/02/01/sebuah-pengumuman-penting/&quot;&gt;closing its door&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a sad an must be hard decision for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/somemandy&quot;&gt;Mandy&lt;/a&gt; and team. &lt;br /&gt;
I am very lucky to be a small part of their journey. hope its for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;good luck in the future project guys!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>eat your own dogfood</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/eat-your-own-dogfood"/>
   <updated>2017-02-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/eat-your-own-dogfood</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This term might be unfamiliar with indonesian, but this is important if you build product and hope people gonna use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A product has a long and sometimes tedious processes, from initiations, designing, architecturing, if the product is a software, doing the coding, go back and forth, finalizing story, bargaining, a lot of process, sometimes drama, and we shipped the product.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Did user happy? who is the user? did we heard their feedback, or if the product is not exist yet, did we do research first? how cooked the story, requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing that sometimes we missed is, did we as someone who make the product use the product itself? did we as the &lt;em&gt;maker&lt;/em&gt; understand what we build? is the product itself speaks our story, and reflected on our product. if the the &lt;em&gt;maker&lt;/em&gt; did not use their own product, how can they understand what people need, we won’t have empathy towards our targetted customers, no sense of ownership, feeld nothing, just plain emotion, work just work, no sense of belonging and urgency whether our product being used by the user or just a bunch of features that they did not need at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the product built by team, and in that organization have multiple team like sales, marketing, products etc, make all the team use it, make all the team get the sense of what our users feels, the crash, the frustations. and in my opinion, it is better if our internal team finds out what went wrong, rather than if our customers in the wild, they can complain, and it’s good, but if they did not, and decided to just not use and uninstall our product, that’s the worst thing that could happened to your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listen your customers feedback, listen their whining, their complain, improve, repeat. 
avoid adding too much feature that sometime the users itself did not need. the feature will overburden the team with no benefit for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;always listen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Life at Jenius</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/life-at-jenius"/>
   <updated>2016-11-25T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/life-at-jenius</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jenius-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;jenius&quot; /&gt;
for the past few month, i’ve been working at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jenius.com&quot;&gt;Jenius&lt;/a&gt;, for those who don’t know, Jenius is a bank, a fintech solution for your everyday lifes #shamelessplug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as an engineer, and have been work at the different company, from solution, bank, ecommerce, and now going back to bank again, at first i thought that it would be boring and enterprise-y, sure, there are few things that enterprisey, few things aren’t, couple things move like startup, the agility, vibrantly and the spirit of the team, probably this is the first fintech who served as a full bank in Indonesia, not just an e-wallet, not just some sort of payment wallet, it’s a bank, you can do things like bank can do, it also support visa, this helps me a lot, i not a fan of credit card, but with this, i could pay like credit card do, Uber, Grab, Play Store, App Store, and if you were fans of Spotify, you could do that also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s a complex system, core bank, its surrounding system, services and so on, things are very exciting if you are a problem solver. and Jenius is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techinasia.com/jobs?query=jenius%20jakarta&quot;&gt;hiring&lt;/a&gt;, hit us up &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jeniusteam@btpn.com&quot;&gt;jeniusteam@btpn.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Extensi file Virtual di Laravel</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/laravel-file-extension"/>
   <updated>2016-08-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/laravel-file-extension</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kasus ini terjadi karena hendak menggunakan Facebook dynamic ads, untuk memenuhi syarat yang ditulis di &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/docs/marketing-api/dynamic-product-ads/product-catalog&quot;&gt;dokumentasi facebook marketing&lt;/a&gt;, dibutuhkan file XML sebagai data feeding ke marketing funnel feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dalam percobaan pertama, hasil response yang digunakan adalah dengan menambahkan &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Content-Type&lt;/code&gt; dioutput, tapi ini tidak cukup, facebook feed fetcher tidak support hal ini, diharuskan berupa ektensi file. memang ada cara bagaimana untuk membuat file feed ini dengan menggunakan facebook Ads SDK, tetapi hal ini mengharuskan kita untuk meng-_update_ &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;composer.json&lt;/code&gt;, dan menambahkan library-nya.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
ada cara yang lebih mudah, yaitu dengan menggunakan &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;routes.php&lt;/code&gt;, dan mendeklarasikan ekstensi file (entah itu pdf, xml, csv dan lainnya),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/dedenf/56c9a236e5f6ae04c516a88895448ed9.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dengan menggunakan entry routes di atas, kita memiliki kemudahan dalam men-_generate_ file, berikut extensinya, di sini, akan terbuat url &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.example.com/products/feed/baju.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ini mirip dengan yang dulu pernah diimplementasikan di codeigniter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dengan cara ini kita bisa dengan mudah menggunakan extensi file semau kita, tanpa perlu ada aktual file-nya, dengan didukung oleh content-type dari hasil output kita.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CMUS</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/cmus"/>
   <updated>2016-08-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/cmus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;found new tool for playing my mp3 collection, on command line interface, it called &lt;a href=&quot;https://cmus.github.io/&quot;&gt;cmus&lt;/a&gt;, you could install it using your package manager (yum, apt, homebrew, &lt;em&gt;etc&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/cmus.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/cmus.png&quot; alt=&quot;CMUS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Go-Jek Privacy Policy</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/on-gojek-term-of-use"/>
   <updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/on-gojek-term-of-use</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Go-Jek is one of the hot startup in Indonesia, operating in major cities in Indonesia, they have massive users, lots of people use their service, from transportation, delivery, cleaning, even massage service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;someone at Telegram group asked is this for real, the Privacy Policy, security section there’s a suprising point, that they are not responsible of their own data. recently gojek was &lt;a href=&quot;http://teknologi.news.viva.co.id/news/read/720973-hacker-bocorkan-lemahnya-keamanan-aplikasi-gojek&quot;&gt;hacked&lt;/a&gt; and leave huge hole in their systems, and its data has been sold in black market.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
this screenshot on their Privacy Policy is their segway if such a thing like data breach like previous ever happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/gojek-provacy-policy.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/gojek-provacy-policy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gojek Privacy Policy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at this terms, i think we should be carefull of what data that you are gonna or already shared with them, ‘cause they are not gonna responsible for your data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Firefox Testpilot</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/firefox-testpilot"/>
   <updated>2016-05-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/firefox-testpilot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently today i tried a feature published by Mozilla Firefox, it called Testpilot, basically it’s a playground for Firefox team to add new feature on their browser, and test it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there are 3 feature that has been rolled out, &lt;a href=&quot;https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/tab-center&quot;&gt;Tab center&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/activity-stream&quot;&gt;Activity Streaming&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://testpilot.firefox.com/experiments/universal-search&quot;&gt;Universal Search&lt;/a&gt;, the most significant is Tab center, it change how we react with Tabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/tabs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mozilla firefox tab center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not hated it, but old habbit die hard, it used to be on the top of the browser, now it moved to the side, a bit weird i think, but let see if it improve the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update (&lt;time datetime=&quot;2016-08-03&quot;&gt;2016-08-03&lt;/time&gt;) :&lt;/strong&gt; they updated the look and feel, and adding few changes, now it displayed page preview instead of favicon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/updated-tabs.png&quot; alt=&quot;mozilla firefox tab center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EYD</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/eyd"/>
   <updated>2016-05-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/eyd</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Penggunaan Ejaan Yang Disempurnakan memang terkadang sangat berat dan terkesan kaku, hal ini dikarenakan penggunaan kata yang baku,
kumpulan kata menjadikan kalimat, dan kalimat ini yang terkesan kaku dikarenakan orang-orang tidak setiap hari mendengar percakapan dengan menggunakan susunan baku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tetapi hal ini bisa jadi berbeda jika dalam bentuk tulisan, tulisan tidak memiliki nada, tetapi memiliki tanda baca, tanda baca ini yang menjadikan satu acuan bagaimana
kita mengartikan atau menginterpretasikan kalimat yang ditulis. contoh: “oleh siapa buku itu ditulis?”, kemudian bandingkan dengan “oleh siapa buku itu ditulis!?”, memiliki susunan 
kata yang sama tetapi memiliki tanda baca yang berbeda, dan hasilnya, berbeda pula pengartian kalimat tersebut di atas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hal yang mungkin terlewat jika kita menggunakan kalimat baku dalam menuliskan tulisan, pesan, surel atau &lt;em&gt;chat&lt;/em&gt; adalah suatu konsistensi, misalkan kita menulis satu surel
dengan kalimat yang kita percaya bernilai baku, kita tidak akan kesulitan dalam mencari surel yang mengandung kata atau kalimat yang kita percaya pernah kita tulis, misalkan waktu itu
saya sedang mencari surel yang mengandung kata “angka, atas, bawah, 0”, konteks yang ada adalah satu susunan kalimat yang kriterianya adalah “angka yang di atas 0 adalah angka yang ditetapkan sebagai harga baru” 
dan bisa ditebak, surel yang mengandung kata “atas, bawah, angka” sangat banyak, dan saya tidak tahu pasti susunan kalimat tepatnya, tapi karena menggunakan kata baku, setidaknya 
banyak surel yang bisa disaring dan bisa menemukan surel yang dimaksud dengan lebih cepat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hal lain yang bisa disebut sebagai kegunaan menggunakan EYD adalah mengurasi risiko salah pengartian, contoh jika kita menuliskan, “baiklah, saya tunggu nanti di Gedung Patra” atau 
“diatas langit, ada langit”, kedua kalimat tersebut menggunakan kata “di”, yang membedakan adalah spasi dengan kalimat selanjutnya, dan berarti beda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebagaimana yang ditulis di atas, tidak semua mau menggunakan EYD dalam berkomunikasi, terkadang menjadi &lt;em&gt;ribet&lt;/em&gt;, tidak tepat guna terkadang, tapi diperlukan sesekali, terutama misalkan jika 
menuliskan surel yang resmi.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Watching The Watcher</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/03/watching-the-watcher"/>
   <updated>2016-03-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/watching-the-watcher</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a constant rant, we have a Job Service defined on our stack, using the very simple tool, Supervisor. this awesome tool do its job, but the thing is, our job service is sucks, and it did not cue or trigger anything if the job stuck/stalled, supervisor assumed that everything is working, because the service is still running, but failed to pass the job and execute it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;all we have to do is restarting the job on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;supervisor&lt;/code&gt;, guess we should refactoring the job service. &lt;em&gt;darn!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>milk+coffee</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/03/custom-brew"/>
   <updated>2016-03-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/custom-brew</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1452882033718-1caccfcfe77f?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=entropy&amp;amp;s=ea55f950e65da5c0e5dfdd4a49424404&quot; alt=&quot;coffee milk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;recently i’ve been lazy, too lazy, no coffee rituals, no fancy brewing tools, also no fancy coffee beans.
i’ve using Nestcafe instant coffee as my caffeine boost, but not just that, here’s my recipe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nescafe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-make-it&quot;&gt;how to make it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first heat the milk (half of the glass/cup/mug), i’m using microwave to heat the milk, after that, add Nescafe instant coffee (add sugar if you want to), mix it, after that pour hot water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tinypress</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/03/tinypress"/>
   <updated>2016-03-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/03/tinypress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinypress.co/&quot;&gt;tinypress&lt;/a&gt;, it might be a good thing to have a publishing platform using github as its engine and also as storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, it provide simplicity yet still looks awesomely hackish™&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>JakartaJS Meetup</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/jakartajs"/>
   <updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/jakartajs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/posts/jakartajs-large.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/jakartajs-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;JakartaJS Meetup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, after hour, finally got a chance to attend one of the hottest Meetup, JakartaJS, even though i came late to the Meetup, but it was fun. Met few friends there, catching up old story with my friend, updating what was what.
The presentation also quite fun, i just got there and people from &lt;strong&gt;Yes Boss&lt;/strong&gt; is already giving their deck, i missed the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>pakeapa and jakartadev</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/chapter"/>
   <updated>2016-02-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/chapter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;last year i bought few domain, i just bought it, and never had a chance to think what am i gonna do with it,
to name a few, i bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://pakeapa.com&quot;&gt;pakeapa.com&lt;/a&gt;, when i decided to bought it, i think of it’s like a blog
that contain information about software, open source or anything else that other people do, have, had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and it turns out it did, even the content has been evolving into like an interview (it did!), it borrows the idea from &lt;a href=&quot;https://usesthis.com&quot;&gt;usesthis&lt;/a&gt;.
and i’m glad Daniel (the onwer of the blog) is pleased and listed pakeapa.com on his site, and he’s such a nice guy, gave some advice of how i could improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second, i bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://jakartadev.org&quot;&gt;Jakartadev.org&lt;/a&gt;, it’s basically a newsletter service, focusing on developers, opensource, technology.
it’s a weekly newsletter, i will send it every monday, it contain a lot of information, tutorial, and tools that you could use to speed up developement,
curated by yours trully, and i hope it will become a habit for me to read tutorials, howto, or anything that could improve my dev skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i hope you enjoy it as much as i do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Setapak Sriwedari</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/08/setapak-sriwedari"/>
   <updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/08/setapak-sriwedari</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;script&gt;
	(function(d, s, id) {
	var js, djs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];
	if (d.getElementById(id)) return;
	js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;
	js.src = &quot;http://as-cdn-files.deezer.com/js/widget/loader.js&quot;;
	 djs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, djs);
}(document, &quot;script&quot;, &quot;deezer-widget-loader&quot;));&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;deezer-widget-player&quot; data-src=&quot;http://www.deezer.com/plugins/player?format=classic&amp;amp;autoplay=false&amp;amp;playlist=false&amp;amp;width=500&amp;amp;height=290&amp;amp;color=1990DB&amp;amp;layout=&amp;amp;size=medium&amp;amp;type=tracks&amp;amp;id=77668337&amp;amp;title=&amp;amp;app_id=1&quot; data-scrolling=&quot;no&quot; data-frameborder=&quot;0&quot; data-allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; data-width=&quot;500&quot; data-height=&quot;290&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>it is hurt</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/06/hurt"/>
   <updated>2015-06-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/06/hurt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/637900/scriptogram/itis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;it fucking hurts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Few coffee reading material</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/04/coffee-reading"/>
   <updated>2015-04-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/04/coffee-reading</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-coffee-of-civilization-in-iceland&quot;&gt;The Coffee of Civilization in Iceland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://indohoy.com/giyanti-coffee-roastery-one-best-coffee-jakarta/&quot;&gt;Giyanti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.minumkopi.com/kedai/12/08/2013/miniatur-kopi-indonesia/&quot;&gt;Miniatur kopi indonesia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jchendra/status/589420121229230080&quot;&gt;Indonesia Latter Art Competition 2015&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ILAC2015?src=hash&quot;&gt;search here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>repeat ad infinitum</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/03/trust"/>
   <updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/03/trust</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/u9XToQO.png&quot; alt=&quot;lastfm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is really no one left at all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>couldn't do it</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/couldnt-do-it"/>
   <updated>2015-02-27T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/couldnt-do-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;something i could not do right now. be cool, not to get angry..&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interstellar</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/interstellar"/>
   <updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/interstellar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As science fiction fans, i love Interstellar, it’s a really great movie, backed by real science and real scientist (who also a robot’s name), not gonna spoiled it, but really it’s a must watch movie. the acting, the cinematography, the visual effect, the deepness of the universe, the silence, and don’t forget the soundtrack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s composed by none other than Hans Zimmer who always worked with Christopher nolan apparently, the music is representing (imo) a thriller and yet a silences of the outer space, that silence, the beating, the instrument helps me forget about the sound, when my ears is not occupied. you can feel it, and helps you forget even for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;https://rd.io/i/Rl6Fs9E-HLMS/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I Should Do This</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/i-should-do-this"/>
   <updated>2015-02-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/i-should-do-this</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/637900/fucking-poster-on-jony-ive-wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;believe in your fucking self&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Here with me</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/here-with-me"/>
   <updated>2015-02-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/here-with me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;wheels are turning
i remember when you were mine
Now just to reach you
Baby, I’d stand in line
…
Don’t want your picture
On my cell phone
I want you here with me
Don’t want your memory
In my head now
I want you here with me
….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://rd.io/i/Rl6Fs9ErU3pl-g/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>M.I.A</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/mia"/>
   <updated>2015-02-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/mia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I want to hold out hope.
But hope is painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-_harold finch_&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>⌘q</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/02/Quit"/>
   <updated>2015-02-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/02/Quit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/637900/okay.png&quot; alt=&quot;okay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>That bad stuff</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/01/we-found-love"/>
   <updated>2015-01-26T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/01/we-found-love</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You almost wish that you could have all that bad stuff back
So that you could have the good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://rd.io/i/Rl6Fs9E-XYj_/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>bekerja</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/01/bekerja"/>
   <updated>2015-01-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2015/01/bekerja</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pernah dengar kalimat yang kira-kira begini:
“…&lt;em&gt;Dia bangun dari pagi hari, terus cari bahan-bahan buat dia jual hari itu, rajin sekali ya? cari uang buat keluarganya, baik pula&lt;/em&gt;.”
atau ini:
“…&lt;em&gt;Dia orang kantoran, kerjanya duduk-duduk depan komputer, kadang ngopi-ngopi di starbucks, meeting ketemu orang, haha-hehe, dapet duit aja.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keduanya adalah salah satu stigma yang ada di masyarakat, tidak menyalahkan apa yang sudah berkembang, hanya saja, orang melihat satu hal tidak dengan melihat hal lain, di mata orang bisa jadi yang dilihat rajin bekerja adalah percakapan pertama, karena yang kedua orangnya hanya duduk-duduk saja, persepsi rajin, kekaguman akan lebih besar kepada orang pertama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bukan iri dengan keadaan, tapi cuma mempertanyakan kenapa memandang berbeda terhadap suatu hal, yang mana ujungnya sama-sama untuk anak-anak mereka, cuma cara mereka yang beda dalam mendapatkan uang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bekerja adalah proses dimana kita menukar satu sumber (waktu, pikiran, modal) untuk mendapatkan sumber yang lain, penukaran ini berbeda-beda caranya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ambil contoh lain, seorang anak menaik hajikan/umroh orang tuanya, satu dengan cara yang bisa dibilang penuh dengan tenaga yang keluar yang dihitung berbeda, jika sumber itu didapat dengan ‘duduk-duduk’, maka itu dihitung ‘kurang rajin’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ini tidak semua orang seperti ini memandang, tapi ada yang berpikir seperti ini, tidak peduli dengan pandangan ini. tapi jika orang yang dikenal berpikir hal yang sama juga, repot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iya ini curhat. mau apa?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Boys Don't Cry</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/12/boys-dont-cry"/>
   <updated>2014-12-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/12/boys-dont-cry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;http://www.deezer.com/plugins/player?autoplay=false&amp;amp;playlist=false&amp;amp;width=700&amp;amp;height=80&amp;amp;cover=true&amp;amp;type=tracks&amp;amp;id=2715862&amp;amp;title=&amp;amp;app_id=undefined&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;80&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>TMUX</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/12/tmux-configuration"/>
   <updated>2014-12-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/12/tmux-configuration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Tmux configuration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/637900/blogs/tmux.png&quot; alt=&quot;tmux config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zsh.org/&quot;&gt;ZSH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamocil.com/&quot;&gt;teamocil&lt;/a&gt;.
[&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dedenf/dotfiles/blob/master/.tmux.conf&quot;&gt;grab the .tmux.conf&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Man and his problems</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/11/my-momma-said"/>
   <updated>2014-11-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/11/my-momma-said</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;my momma said, i’ll be alright.
my momma said, everything you’ll do that’s because you want it.
my momma said, nothing ever last forever.
my momma said, you need to be more open.
my momma said, is that you?
my momma said, this is not who you are.
my momma said, this is not the reflection of your father.
my momma said, i want you to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Minimum Viable Infrastructure</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/10/minimum-viable-infrastructure"/>
   <updated>2014-10-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/10/minimum-viable-infrastructure</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Programmer Flowchart</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/10/programmer-flowchart"/>
   <updated>2014-10-10T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/10/programmer-flowchart</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BhZ0MHoCcAABGut.jpg:large&quot; alt=&quot;might be true&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yes, this might be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TrueValhalla/status/438665765265240064&quot;&gt;@TrueValhalla&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Milky way</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/10/milkyway"/>
   <updated>2014-10-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/10/milkyway</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/static/archives/images/screen/ann0912a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;milky way&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i think this track suits well, i love stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;http://www.deezer.com/plugins/player?autoplay=false&amp;amp;playlist=false&amp;amp;width=542&amp;amp;height=80&amp;amp;cover=true&amp;amp;type=album&amp;amp;id=7769437&amp;amp;title=&amp;amp;app_id=undefined&quot; width=&quot;542&quot; height=&quot;80&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(image via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spacetelescope.org/images/ann0912a/&quot;&gt;NASA &amp;amp; ESA&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>D'Cinnamons</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/10/dcinnamons"/>
   <updated>2014-10-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/10/dcinnamons</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, it’s an -old- album, but still love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; src=&quot;http://www.deezer.com/plugins/player?autoplay=false&amp;amp;playlist=true&amp;amp;width=700&amp;amp;height=240&amp;amp;cover=true&amp;amp;type=album&amp;amp;id=7538440&amp;amp;title=&amp;amp;app_id=undefined&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;240&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What Changed?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/09/git-whatchanged"/>
   <updated>2014-09-27T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/09/git-whatchanged</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;sometime i wish i could just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-whatchanged.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ life whatchanged&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and i could see what has been changed in my whole life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
...
commit 353da0e5649dc910ca7fe1d52bcf10dbf2ae4b36
Author: deden fathurahman &amp;lt;dedenf@example-life.com&amp;gt;
Date:   Tue Jan 07 08:30:32 2014 +0700

	You are waking up, and felt happy.

...
...
commit aff79808a718b54cabf8b749705ad6c039b0ced0
Author: deden fathurahman &amp;lt;dedenf@example-life.com&amp;gt;
Date:   Sat Sep 27 08:30:32 2014 +0700

	Eating custard cake, you gain some calories.
	oh are you happy now?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Be yourself</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/09/yourself"/>
   <updated>2014-09-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/09/yourself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Be yourself;
Everyone else is already taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Oscar Wilde&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Di kereta</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/09/di-kereta"/>
   <updated>2014-09-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/09/di-kereta</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Beberapa waktu ini, dengan pekerjaan baru yang jaraknya lumayan dari tempat tinggal, menuju tempat kerja yang di daerah utara dari arah selatan memang lumayan memakan waktu, dan dilakukanlah semacam eksperimen dengan menggunakan moda dan trayek yang ditempuh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pertama yang saya coba adalah memakai bis transjakarta, dengan menaiki koridor 9 arah pluit, dan kemudian transit melanjutkan ke arah kota total waktu yang dibutuhkan 2.5 jam plus menunggu bis transit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kemudian dicoba dengan menggunakan koridor 1 arah blok - kota, memakan waktu 2 jam, waktu yang masih cukup lama, karena yang paling memakan waktu adalah perjalan ke arah karet, kemudian dilanjut menuju halte transjakarta karet 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cara ke-3 adalah dengan menggunakan kereta, dengan menggunakan moda tersebut, sampai ke tempat kerja kurang lebih memakan waktu sejam, lebih cepat dari penggunaan 2 moda trayek di atas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hal yang diperhatikan ketika menggunakan kereta, banyak orang yang saling kenal satu sama lainnya, walaupun mereka bukan teman sepekerjaan, banyak yang memang kenal di atas kereta ketika mereka menuju ke tempat yang sama atau melalui trayek yang sama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hal yang baru, melihat orang yang terkadang saling sapa menanyakan “kemana aja, pak?”, mungkin mereka tidak saling kenal nama, tapi kenal dengan muka dan pembawaan masing-masing, teman bernama @randhaem, pengguna setia KRL commuter line bercerita, terkadang dia hafal dimana penumpang yang biasa bareng turun, terkadang tidak ada percakapan sebelumnya, dan saling tegur ketika salah satu dari mereka turun terlebih dahulu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sepengalaman, hal baru ini tentu tidak akan ditemui di moda lain selain di kereta.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Crack your code</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/07/crack-your-code"/>
   <updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/07/crack-your-code</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s amazing I’m in this maze with you
I just can’t crack your code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the days goes on and on, you got no proper tools.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Penamaan URL yang lebih baik</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/04/penamaan-url-lebih-baik"/>
   <updated>2014-04-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2014/04/penamaan-url-lebih-baik</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hari ini mendapat tautan mengenenai sistem pengawasan perlindungan konsumen di situs kemendag, tautan yang dibuat adalah &lt;a href=&quot;http://siswaspk.kemendag.go.id/&quot;&gt;http://siswaspk.kemendag.go.id/&lt;/a&gt;, sangat tidak intuitif dan mungkin susah diingat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kenapa tidak dibuat yang lebih sederhana dan dimengerti, misalkan &lt;a href=&quot;http://pengaduan.kemendag.go.id/konsumen/&quot;&gt;http://pengaduan.kemendag.go.id/konsumen/&lt;/a&gt; kata ‘konsumen’ bisa ditambahkan lagi jika ada sistem lain misalkan pengaduan pedagang.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Right Thing</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/12/the-right-thing"/>
   <updated>2013-12-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/12/the-right-thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;spoilers: there is no the right thing. &lt;br /&gt;
at least for something you didn’t know or something you thing you didn’t know, you have to walk through it to get the answer, there’s no The Oracle who can guide you make your choice. how can you tell which decision is right or wrong? well you don’t, at least until you live with that decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you watch The Matrix trilogy movie, there’s a lot scene and dialog involving choices, here’s one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Neo: But if you already know, how can I make a choice? The Oracle: Because you didn’t come here to make the choice, you’ve already made it. You’re here to try to understand why you made it. I thought you’d have figured that out by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/quotes?item=qt0283092&quot;&gt;imdb link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oracle is a powerful program, she cannot say what Neo should do with his own choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and please, there is no such thing as coincidence. everything happen as it is. there’s no adjustment bureau, or yourself from the future to change what choices you’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kano</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/kano"/>
   <updated>2013-11-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/kano</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;found a kickstarter project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/alexklein/kano-a-computer-anyone-can-make&quot;&gt;Kano&lt;/a&gt;, what a great project. AND I WANT ONE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/alexklein/kano-a-computer-anyone-can-make/widget/video.html&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>you are a dent in the universe</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/dent-in-universe"/>
   <updated>2013-11-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/dent-in-universe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re here to put a dent in the universe. Otherwise why else even be here?
—Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Share your dream</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/share-your-dream"/>
   <updated>2013-11-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/share-your-dream</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/n5H7RtY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;share your dream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Music pick - Spanish Prisoners</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/music-pick-spanish-prisoners"/>
   <updated>2013-11-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/music pick-spanish-prisoners</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;if you love gloomy, dreamy melodic guitar like post-rock, you’ll love this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2428500762/size=medium/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/transparent=true/&quot; seamless=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spanishprisoners.bandcamp.com/album/gold-fools&quot;&gt;Gold Fools by Spanish Prisoners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The holstee manifesto</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/the-holstee"/>
   <updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/the-holstee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/G8RRuaJ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the holstee manifesto&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How coffee transformed someone's life</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/10/how-coffee-transformed-life"/>
   <updated>2013-10-31T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/10/how-coffee-transformed-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;watching at this video, i’m envy to the people who found their passion and they love doing what the wanted to do.
it’s not just the coffee, it’s their story that makes this talk is thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/1COwy_xiw_g&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Violent</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/10/quote-one"/>
   <updated>2013-10-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/10/quote-one</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The most violent element in society is ignorance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emma Goldman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Perfect Day</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/10/perfect-day"/>
   <updated>2013-10-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/10/perfect-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I heard &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lou_Reed&quot;&gt;Lou reed&lt;/a&gt; from a friend when i was in college, and this is the first song i’ve been listening to, love it. sadly he &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/lou-reed-velvet-underground-leader-and-rock-pioneer-dead-at-71-20131027&quot;&gt;died at 71&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♫ &lt;a href=&quot;http://ex.fm/song/1gk8jg&quot;&gt;Lou Reed - Perfect Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/37742254&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;375&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Music pick - Asobi Seksu</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/10/farewell"/>
   <updated>2013-10-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/10/farewell</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday i heard about Asobi Seksu, when i’m browsing at last.fm looking for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.last.fm/music/Blonde+Redhead&quot;&gt;Blonde Readhead&lt;/a&gt; entries, and stumble upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.last.fm/music/Asobi+Seksu/&quot;&gt;Asobi Seksu&lt;/a&gt;, and found their music is also mesmerizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♫ &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/sargent-house/asobi-seksu-farewell&quot;&gt;Asobi Seksu - Farewell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/65748504&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Disconnected</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/10/disconnected"/>
   <updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/10/disconnected</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elezea.com/2012/11/a-life-less-posted/&quot;&gt;A life less posted&lt;/a&gt;, a story about how awesome we could spend our time with our significant other, without a ‘burden’ to share, a ‘burden’ about how we socialize with others. Some might say that if we’re not on facebook or other social media site, we didn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we share almost everything, what we eat, what we wear, who we go out, and we share our own children, post them online with no consideration whatsoever. is that good or bad? i don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How you enjoy your coffee?</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/09/how-you-enjoy-your-coffee"/>
   <updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/09/how-you-enjoy-your-coffee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/OA8tMR9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;coffee bean&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you love coffee? i know i do, got enough plenty variety of coffee in my house, and some processing tools that helps me enjoy my coffee.
i know i love it, and of course enjoy it, i love to choose my beans, i love grinding my coffee beans (roasting is another level that i hadn’t mastered yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but this can be a problem for some hipster, the so-called coffee-lover, they tend to preach and critize how other people make their own coffee, some people love to add sugar, or maybe adding some cream, milk or some other ingredients that people will enjoy, so be it, that’s how people enjoy their own cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Something in the air</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/09/something-in-the-air"/>
   <updated>2013-09-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/09/something-in-the-air</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;you won’t have THAT something in the air if all the air is being sucked away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, let’s make some coffee, dear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/40980282&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/40980282&quot;&gt;AeroPress “Ritual”&lt;/a&gt;
from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/sandwichvideo&quot;&gt;Sandwich Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wish You Were Here</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/08/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here"/>
   <updated>2013-08-30T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/08/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7dxps5BGw1rbrdrco1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;wish you were here&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re just two lost souls
Swimming in a fish bowl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♪ &lt;a href=&quot;http://ex.fm/song/1evtba&quot;&gt;Pink Floyd - Wish you were here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Current reading list</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/08/reading-list"/>
   <updated>2013-08-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/08/reading-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computerandvideogames.com/421728/features/the-boy-who-beat-ocarina-of-time-in-22-minutes/&quot;&gt;The boy who beat Ocarina of Time in 22 minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.bufferapp.com/10-scientifically-proven-ways-to-make-yourself-happier&quot;&gt;10 Simple Things You Can Do Today That Will Make You Happier, Backed By Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mind-the-body/5e4bd73430dd&quot;&gt;A Chef and Doctor Talk About Butter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/7/24/your-app-makes-me-fat&quot;&gt;Your app makes me fat — Serious Pony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Most Astounding Fact</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/08/most-astounding-fact"/>
   <updated>2013-08-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/08/most-astounding-fact</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/38101676?color=00c4ff&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/38101676&quot;&gt;The Most Astounding Fact&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/maxschlick&quot;&gt;Max Schlickenmeyer&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spoofing mac address</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/07/spoofing-mac-address"/>
   <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/07/spoofing-mac-address</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;another tool that i use for covering my ass from tracking beside my tunnel tool, i use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/feross/SpoofMAC&quot;&gt;spoof-mac&lt;/a&gt;, a python library that can be called from your lovely terminal, you could install it via &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip install SpoofMAC&lt;/code&gt;.
run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo spoof-mac randomize wi-fi&lt;/code&gt; and you’ll get a random mac address assigned to your ether. you could set the spoof-mac to run everytime you boot up your machine and before joining the network (see their github project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or maybe if you don’t want to install spoof-mac you could always use good old fashion &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt; by runnning this command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo ifconfig en0 ether xx:xx:xx:xx:xx:xx&lt;/code&gt; (remember, use hex for macaddr). or you can use a generated value by using this &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;openssl rand -hex 6 | sed 's/\(..\)/\1:/g; s/.$//'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My ten most frequent Command line</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/ten-cli-command"/>
   <updated>2013-06-29T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/ten-cli-command</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://coderwall.com/p/o5qijw&quot;&gt;the tip post&lt;/a&gt; from coderwall, and here’s my result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Kp2djiL.png&quot; alt=&quot;10 commands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I hate SVN</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/hate-svn"/>
   <updated>2013-06-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/hate-svn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;svn: The path ‘.’ appears to be part of a Subversion 1.7 or greater working copy.
Please upgrade your Subversion client to use this to your bash profile. working copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tmux copy paste with mouse on MacOSX</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/tmux-copy-paste"/>
   <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/tmux-copy-paste</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;using &lt;a href=&quot;http://tmux.sourceforge.net&quot;&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt; is great for your productivity. so, by default tmux is not capable doing copy pasting using your mouse by dragging text and then right click copy as usual. here’s what you can do, by pressing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;option&lt;/code&gt; and select what text that you want to copy at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Want! Selvedge Sleeves</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/selvedge-sleeves"/>
   <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/selvedge-sleeves</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://uncrate.com/p/2010/11/selvedge-sleeves-xl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Selvedge Sleeves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denim! WANT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncrate.com/stuff/selvedge-sleeves/&quot;&gt;uncrate&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time-lapse of the Galactic Center</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/galactic-center"/>
   <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/galactic-center</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Galactic Center at zenith Paranal observatory, a whole sky time-lapse video of the galactic center by Astrophotographer &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/sguisard&quot;&gt;Stéphane Guisard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/68260417&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome video!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2013/06/you-are-here-a-whole-sky-time-lapse-of-the-galactic-center/276891/&quot;&gt;@TheAtlantic&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Full path info on title</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/st-fullpath"/>
   <updated>2013-06-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/st-fullpath</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;if you want to have full path information in your sublime text window title. open User preference, add this line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“show_full_path”: true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Another Google reader alternative</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/google-reader-alt"/>
   <updated>2013-06-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/google-reader-alt</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/yg6WuL0.png&quot; alt=&quot;readable.css&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we may know, Google will shutdown google reader, a much beloved rss reader/service that many users have used it as their daily activity. i’ve been using Google reader for a long time, as alternative i’ve found &lt;a href=&quot;http://theoldreader.com/&quot;&gt;The Old Reader&lt;/a&gt; as my replacement for Google Reader, Today i found about &lt;a href=&quot;http://readable.cc/&quot;&gt;redable.cc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not like usual rss reader that has ‘folder’ like icon, but instead it has a list with big heading information about what rss that we’ve been subscribed. it has a simple interface with serif typeface all over the place (which is a good thing for readable purpose).
Think i might use it for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading List</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/reading-list"/>
   <updated>2013-06-13T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/reading-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;reading list this week, still digging about API, its scale, optimization, what kinda resource do i need for upcoming/current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoq.com/news/2013/02/netflix-api-optimization&quot;&gt;The Netflix API Optimization Story&lt;/a&gt;
this should be an epic read&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mechanical-sympathy.blogspot.com/2013/02/cpu-cache-flushing-fallacy.html&quot;&gt;CPU Cache Flushing Fallacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.bocoup.com/node-stress-test-server/&quot;&gt;Realtime Node.js App: Building a Server&lt;/a&gt;
Friend of mine is building an API for the app that one of the largest telco company in indonesia build, it used Node.js as its communication between internal telco’s API and application layer and talk to the clients mobile app. so maybe i’ll take a look for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Eye tracking study on CamelCase and under_score style</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/eye-tracking-study"/>
   <updated>2013-06-13T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/eye-tracking-study</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Title:
Date: 2013-06-13 00:00
Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kent.edu/~jmaletic/papers/ICPC2010-CamelCaseUnderScoreClouds.pdf&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Bonita Sharif and Jonathan I. Maletic from Department of Computer Science
Kent State University about how the eye response to camelCase and under_score indentifier, or might be function or variable naming style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Visual effort is determined using six measures based on eye gaze data namely: fixation counts and durations. Although, no
difference was found between identifier styles with respect to accuracy, results indicate a significant improvement in time and lower visual effort with the underscore style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;personally, i like underscore rather than camelCase, it’s more readable and concise, and easily to read between word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.kent.edu/~jmaletic/papers/ICPC2010-CamelCaseUnderScoreClouds.pdf&quot;&gt;Paper Link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mixtape Breathe</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-breathe"/>
   <updated>2013-06-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-breathe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://8tracks.imgix.net/i/000/423/929/c/bbr-3640.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;breathe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this mixtape was made for my significant other. still, it has genre of Triphop, electronic, ambient and post-rock. featured artist is Télépopmusik, Dido, and indonesian Triphop/electronic group &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.last.fm/music/Homogenic&quot;&gt;Homogenic&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;some of the tracks listed below
♫ &lt;a href=&quot;http://8tracks.com/dedenf/breathe&quot;&gt;8Tracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Télépopmusik - Breathe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air - Playground Love&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everybody loves Irene - Rindu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Röyksopp - Eple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Massive Attack - Inertia Creeps
…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;the cover is slightly cut almost half of it&lt;/em&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://inspcollection.com/post/4070889611&quot;&gt;photo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>16 common mistake young startup make</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/common-startup-mistake"/>
   <updated>2013-06-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/common-startup-mistake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;mashable has wrapup the that mistake by young startup often did, here’s the recap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgoing Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waiting Too Long to Launch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiring Poorly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not Embracing Agility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guarding The “Big Idea”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Losing Focus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assuming Virality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obsessing Over Funding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chasing Investors Instead of Befriending Investees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dwelling on Things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting Distracted By Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not Having the Right Co-Founder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trying to Win Over Everyone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not Listening to Current (or Future) Customers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jumping to Decisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not Maintaining Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’d like to mention point 2, it’s like every young startup did it, from their persfective, they want to impress their users with bunch of feature at once, but this is the main reason that sometimes they delayed the launch date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2013/06/10/startup-mistakes/&quot;&gt;mashable&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Server Name</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/server-name"/>
   <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/server-name</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;as been discussed on id-gmail mailing list, naming a server name is hard, sometimes you have to pick a theme for your servers, there’s some who named their server using mountain name, or using Myth Gods names, and sometime some lady’s names like dewi, julie.
it’s hard because sometimes once you named one of your server you should know its purpose, its capabilities based on their representative name, for example Zeus, it’s a main server that have a significant purpose on the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;xkcd.com&quot;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/permanence.png&quot;&gt;nailed it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/permanence.png&quot; alt=&quot;permanance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My dream backup scheme</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/my-dream-backup-scheme"/>
   <updated>2013-06-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/my-dream-backup-scheme</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey it’s rhyme!
on my system right now, i have two timemachine who backed up my entire system, one i had it on my whole dedicated external drive, it’s an old 320GB Seagate drive, and in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_Attached_Storage&quot;&gt;DAS&lt;/a&gt; system (i named it “Kimu Garden”, because it’s sounds beautiful) as a backup in sparsedisk image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my 320GB Seagate drive i’m using plain TimeMachine app, as for sparsedisk i use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bombich.com/&quot;&gt;carbon copy cloner&lt;/a&gt; (i use the free one) as backup app, maybe having 2 backup for my machine is overkill, but hey, nobody knows when shit happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my work files is on dropbox, exclude the codes, all my code is either on TimeMachine or in the Sparsedisk image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i also subscribed to other online backup system, i use GDrive, Skydrive. but one thing about skydrive, it’s allows you to upload the file without having to syncronize it on to your machine, which is great, i uploaded some of the sensitive data on to it, with sparsedisk protection of course, and doesn’t have to mirror that file on my machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i want to have a system that can do the backup for me, i heard backblaze have amazing service and cheap comparing to the other services&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Postman</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/postman"/>
   <updated>2013-06-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/postman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IFgsFPM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;postman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://coderwall.com/dedenf&quot;&gt;coderwall&lt;/a&gt; page, i wrote about &lt;a href=&quot;https://coderwall.com/p/kw6mbg?i=2&amp;amp;p=1&amp;amp;q=author%3Adedenf&amp;amp;t%5B%5D=dedenf&quot; title=&quot;osx http client url&quot;&gt;OSX HTTP client&lt;/a&gt;, it’s a great app, but sometimes i want more of it, i want to craft the request intuitively with easy option to set up, and i want it without have to open another app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long came &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.getpostman.com/&quot;&gt;PostMan&lt;/a&gt;, a chrome extension and A powerful HTTP client to test REST web services. a tool that i use extensively for the past 2 month, it support many http verb that RESTafarian would fall in love with. go ahead, try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(direct link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/postman-rest-client/fdmmgilgnpjigdojojpjoooidkmcomcm/related&quot;&gt;chrome webstore&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;photo are taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/thedownstairslounge/6435380929&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Postman_Pat&quot;&gt;Postman Pat&lt;/a&gt;, a series that Athar used to watch on JimJam.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Run</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/runnnn"/>
   <updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/runnnn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/67676730&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;311&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;i wanna run&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Infrastructure as code</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/infrastructure-as-code"/>
   <updated>2013-06-07T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/infrastructure-as-code</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/21814324&quot; width=&quot;490&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/jedi4ever/infrastructure-as-code-abug-session&quot; title=&quot;Infrastructure as Code - ABUG Session&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code - ABUG Session&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/jedi4ever&quot;&gt;Patrick Debois&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Every WWDC Banner Ever For The Last 11 Years</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/wwdc-11-years-banner"/>
   <updated>2013-06-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/wwdc-11-years-banner</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;impressive collection of WWDC banner for 11 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cultofmac.com/171434/every-wwdc-banner-ever-for-the-last-10-years-gallery/&quot;&gt;@cultofmac&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mixtape apart</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-apart"/>
   <updated>2013-06-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-apart</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgix.8tracks.com/i/000/407/643/c/apart-3255.png&quot; alt=&quot;apart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;currently listening to blue october lately, especially 18th Floor Balcony. and there also daft punk’s newest album.
this mixtape consist 11 tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♫ &lt;a href=&quot;http://8tracks.com/dedenf/apart&quot;&gt;8tracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blue October - 18th Floor Balcony&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lana del ray - Summertime sadness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;R.E.M - The One i Love&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snow Patrol - Chasing Cars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stereophonic - Dakota&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sting - Fragile&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wannadies - Shortly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daft Punk - Get Lucky (feat. Pharrell Williams)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Robyn - Every Tear Drop Is A Waterfall (covers)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eagle Eye Cherry - Save Tonight&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Travis - Closer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Installing Laravel 4, oneliner</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/oneline-laravel"/>
   <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/oneline-laravel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;downloading package or setup composer.json could become a hassle.
instead, just go with this one line of command on terminal. make sure you already installed composer and put it in the system wide bin (eg. /usr/local/bin/).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ composer create-project laravel/laravel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this command also work if you want to setup a new package on composer packagist repo. for example installing Slimframework &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;composer create-project slim/slim&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New office</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/new-office"/>
   <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/new-office</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;it’s been more than one month since i’m joining new office, my responsisbily now is as API developer, currently working at game publisher company, so much different from where i’ve been regarding the business process etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s always hard to leave my previous job, at least for me, more than three years working with wonderful team, so many jokes that we invented there, so many memories.
we also have a soon to be launch product, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kineria.com/&quot;&gt;kineria.com&lt;/a&gt; a movie streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this time i’m building an API interface system and also build a social network for indonesian gamers, pretty much like Gree+Line, just starting my adventure here, we’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, did you game today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: previous photo is my new office.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This is blasphemy, this is ...</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/blasphemy"/>
   <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/blasphemy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/eb10cjH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;this..&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Markdown with custom css class test</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/big-text"/>
   <updated>2013-06-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/big-text</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;big-text&quot;&gt;
So, this &lt;span class=&quot;medium-big-text font-della&quot;&gt;should&lt;/span&gt; be a &lt;span class=&quot;very-big font-sail&quot;&gt;big&lt;/span&gt; text
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mixtape Trip-ish</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-one"/>
   <updated>2013-06-04T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/mixtape-one</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgix.8tracks.com/mix_covers/000/570/340/27602.original.jpg?fm=jpg&amp;amp;q=65&amp;amp;sharp=15&amp;amp;vib=10&amp;amp;w=1024&amp;amp;h=1024&amp;amp;fit=max&quot; alt=&quot;trip-ish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;liked the mixtape, full of Triphop artist, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portishead_(band)&quot;&gt;Portishead&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lamb_(band)&quot;&gt;Lamb&lt;/a&gt;, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;♫ &lt;a href=&quot;http://8tracks.com/shirink/trip-ish&quot;&gt;8tracks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to negotiate, Steve Job's style.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/06/stevejobs-negotiate"/>
   <updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/06/stevejobs-negotiate</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://qz.com/87184/the-steve-jobs-emails-that-show-how-to-win-a-hard-nosed-negotiation/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, it shows how steve jobs negotiate with HarperCollins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe I’m missing something, but I don’t see any other alternatives. Do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Something you know</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/05/something-you-know"/>
   <updated>2013-05-01T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/05/something-you-know</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jetpants is an automation toolkit for handling monstrously large MySQL database topologies. It is geared towards common operational tasks like cloning slaves, rebalancing shards, and performing master promotions. It features a command suite for easy use by operations staff, though it’s also a full Ruby library for use in developing custom migration scripts and database automation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Reader</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/03/google-reader"/>
   <updated>2013-03-21T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/03/google-reader</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google reader will say its goodbye on July 1st 2013..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/H1Sumib.png&quot; alt=&quot;my reading history&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Grown up</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/03/grown-ups"/>
   <updated>2013-03-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/03/grown-ups</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;read a post from &lt;a href=&quot;http://daltoncaldwell.com/&quot;&gt;dalton caldwell&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;http://daltoncaldwell.com/touring-by-yourself&quot;&gt;Touring yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i love this quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Going “indie” is clearly not for everyone, but I have the utmost respect for the people that are able and willing to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you read the whole post, you’ll get what his meant. and i think personally, there’s a connection of how you become a grown ups, especially when you were married, you support your family by what you were doing right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that kinda responsibility is not bounded by age, any age who matches criteria like supporting family and the love ones is considered a grown-ups, responsible for himself and other.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hipsterized commit</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/03/hispterize-commit"/>
   <updated>2013-03-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/03/hispterize commit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After adding current listened track into my commit message, now i’m adding the action, i take picture everytime commiting something. here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get ImageSnap
 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brew install imagesnap&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;port install imagesnap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create this hook at your project .git/hooks/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;COMMITID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;git rev-parse HEAD&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
imagesnap &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-q&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-w&lt;/span&gt; 1 .gitsnap/&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$COMMITID&lt;/span&gt;.jpg&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;save as post-commit (so it will run after commit)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to stop procrastination</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/stop-procrastination"/>
   <updated>2013-02-28T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/stop-procrastination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;did you always stuck in the morning reading news, hundred of rss feed, Flipboarding(?), and last but not least, Twitter or Facebook. they can suck all of your productive time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but there’s a way to satisfy your need to tweets or update you status. you can use the tool that [hipster(?)] developer already knows, GIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see, i have a record &lt;strong&gt;7.777&lt;/strong&gt; tweets right now, and i hate to break this number. and guess what, yes, i’ve been ranting/tweeting/etc via my commit message. This way i can get both satisfaction, by writing not-all-nonsense so-called tweet and i can get productive by making change on my code, if i want to ‘tweet’, i have to change/write codes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: i can also wrote a ‘blog’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dedenf/vagrant/commit/7467f6c1708795016818718e2dd66fda82645a93&quot;&gt;like this one&lt;/a&gt;, besides for my technical stuff i’ve been blogging on &lt;a href=&quot;https://coderwall.com/dedenf&quot;&gt;coderwall.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/hy1kOgg.png&quot; alt=&quot;lovely number&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Git commit and mood</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/git-commit-and-mood"/>
   <updated>2013-02-27T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/git-commit-and-mood</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;many developers push their code to git repo with funny or sometimes silly comments (i do that sometimes) like this &lt;a href=&quot;http://whatthecommit.com/&quot;&gt;whatthecommit&lt;/a&gt; site, but maybe it will be more hips (like hipsters do) if i can fetch last.fm api from current listened music and add them to my commit message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here’s the idea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ git commit -m &quot;fixing some bugs $(last_fm)&quot; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the last command is to insert my last.fm current track.
so if we browse the log it will be shown &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;fixing some bugs while listening to U2 - Stay&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. if i don’t listened any track it will return &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;with no music&quot;&lt;/code&gt; (or any other message).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update 2013-03-05&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/93x0bpc.png&quot; alt=&quot;hispter geek&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/dedenf/5097395&quot;&gt;gists on github&lt;/a&gt; of course&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It means we are productive</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/git-commit"/>
   <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/git-commit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/evpKeCw.png&quot; alt=&quot;commit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mou &#9829; scriptogr.am</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/mou-scriptogram"/>
   <updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/mou-scriptogram</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;i know it’s late, but just stumbling that we can post to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptogr.am&quot;&gt;scriptogr.am&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://mouapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/RROdN0e.png&quot; alt=&quot;scriptogr.am ID from Mou app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you are Mac users, Mou is the best app for markdown, and it’s free!.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Charts that you need</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/three-charts"/>
   <updated>2013-02-07T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/three-charts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/writers/noah&quot;&gt;Noah&lt;/a&gt; at 37signal made a list about the chart that he need to display data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When you want to show how something has changed over time, use a line chart.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When you want to show how something is distributed, use a histogram.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;When you want to display summary information, use a table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seeing this chart type for people other than devops people or developer i think it’s enough to display data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vagrantfile for everyday use</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/vagrant-everyday"/>
   <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/vagrant-everyday</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;built up this repo to share my everyday use vagrant configuration on my local machine, i use Centos 6.3 as my basebox, there’s 3 instance right now, running different purposes, talk to each other, they having threesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;clone, fork &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://github.com/dedenf/vagrant&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It's been a while</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/been-a-while"/>
   <updated>2013-02-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/been-a-while</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;yeapno&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What a day</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/02/what-a-day"/>
   <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/02/what-a-day</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;yesterday, a site that i help build, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wujudkan.com&quot;&gt;wujudkan.com&lt;/a&gt; is launched, for those who don’t know wujudkan is, it’s a crowd funding site, that helps creative talent, or someone who wants to build something and need some fundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it took a lot of confident to launch it, since so many little things that we have to handle, from the working codes, redactional text, email etc. from many startup advice, launch as soon as possible is essential, to get users feedback you have to launch your product, to get to know what is wrong with your app is launch it. so by today, i look at the Google Analytics, it was quite good, from the developers perspective, the site is running just fine, no choke, no database overload, maybe because the traffic is just average (dunno, though).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/3Q3r19053a390s08300d/Screen%20Shot%202012-02-22%20at%2012.58.36%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;stats&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/032E2S1p3j38181f1W1O/Screen%20Shot%202012-02-22%20at%2012.58.46%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;another stat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and now for the engagement to the users, from the beginning, the team has already using social media tools to make an introductory to the users. the feedback from twitter channel is quite positive, they help us by reporting bugs and what features they want. so i guess now is the time for some bug squashing and development.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Modernizr vs IE</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/02/modernizr-vs-ie"/>
   <updated>2012-02-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/02/modernizr-vs-ie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today, i’ve found out something weird, we took an internal launch of our newly developed app that display numerous graph and statistics, it went crash. not the app, but the browser, and you can guess, it’s IE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From IE6 on XP sp2 until IE8 on windows 7, it all went crash, first i thought about many ‘add-ons’ like Yahoo! websearch (curse you!), and other kind of IE rubbish. i’m heading to the code to look something that might be not right, first i disabled header() from the code, but it’s not it, and the look at the doctype, maybe
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--[if lt IE 7]&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;![endif]--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;delete that line, but still it doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ook a shot disabled Modernizr (mine is v2.0.6), and it went ok, that’s the ‘culprit’ behind the IE6-IE8 assasinations, as usual, went to google, stumbling at the Modernizr github repo to see maybe other users experienced the same thing, and yes, there is. many &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/scottjehl/Respond/issues/27&quot;&gt;asking&lt;/a&gt; about the positioning of the Modernizr call, is it before css, or after css calls. the documentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.modernizr.com/docs/#installing&quot;&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; that to install Modernizr is after CSS calls. went to see my code again, it is after CSS calls, a mystery that should be solve, but it’s not, the IE still crashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, i just disabled the Modernizr, because can’t find any windows machine right now, too much if i’m firing my VM right now. but i still do believe that placing jQuery and Modernizr is the problem, and some about some CSS3 code that i’ve written, oh they all plotted together to kill our beloved IE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well, time to write about Sherlock’s ending.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Codeigniter Cache Tips</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/01/codeigniter-cache"/>
   <updated>2012-01-16T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/01/codeigniter-cache</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cache system in Codeigniter is a quite nice feature, thanks to its modular system, you can add more than just a built in cache system, you can add your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you want to make an app with search feature, if you don’t implement cache feature in it, the app will always ask the database whether it has the data or not, this could make your database work for just a ‘historical’ data.
to make things faster, use cache. to get this cache (even it’s in-memory or in-file cache) work, you could make a GET method (or if you have to use POST, that’s ok, will work too) and create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/URI&quot;&gt;URI&lt;/a&gt; for that search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for example, if you want to cache a user information, just put ?key=user_name in URI, so that the URI will be saved as cache by your app (of course you must enable the cache system on config file!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“what if the user information is changed?”, yes, if the user information is changed your cache will be something  to blame if the information is not updated instantly. to make this work, just delete the cache if there’s a update action in your module, with that you’ll get the same result after its get updated&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Playing with Twitter Bootstrap</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/01/playing-with-twitter-bootstrap"/>
   <updated>2012-01-12T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/01/playing-with-twitter-bootstrap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been playing with twitter bootstrap for a while now, i’m considering to make this bootstrap template as my starting point of my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the past 3 days, i’ve been working creating a &lt;a href=&quot;http://patungan.co&quot;&gt;patungan&lt;/a&gt; design template. lots of tear to create a slightly similar look to &lt;a href=&quot;http://kickstarter.com&quot;&gt;kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;look at this &lt;a href=&quot;http://d.pr/Fh6R&quot;&gt;design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and now, trying to build a forecasting systemm. still using the same basic bootstrap template from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/&quot;&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, creating smart app tool like forecasting system is take a while, regarding of the formula, mining past data and so on.
for now, i’m making my own design system, taking from couple of source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;patungan is renamed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wujudkan.com&quot;&gt;wujudkan.com&lt;/a&gt;, go make some project over there!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Not To great</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/01/not-to-great"/>
   <updated>2012-01-09T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/01/not-to-great</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;with all this deadline, i think i’m about to explode.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>If i were Facebook</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2011/01/if-i-were-facebook"/>
   <updated>2011-01-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/01/if-i-were-facebook</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;i will buy Last.fm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;create a ‘channel-app-like’, so we’ve got status stream (text), photos, video, and last but not least, Audio. that’s where Last.fm coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as we know that Spotify is already built in to the Facebook, it’s easier to integrate both of them. status flooding is something that many user would not love, so for the audio, the traffic will be huge, don’t bother about putting what other people listened into their wall. just don’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
